Alright, in this lesson, we'll cover the basics of Python.
Functions.
And the reason we start with this is because
we mentioned earlier that when getting started,
we can begin with the backend.
Our backend is developed using the Python language.
So, we need to familiarize ourselves with Python,
and go over some fundamental syntax.
Let's dive into that.
I won't go into too much detail, though.
We just need to cover enough to get started.
So, let's take a look.
First, we're developing in PYTHM.
So, we need to create a project here.
Let's open iCharm.
There are a few interfaces.
In this case,
just click on 'New Project'.
If in this situation
Another scenario is when we delete this
We bring up this situation
We click here
Create a new project
Then, where do we save it?
I'm saving it in the sixth lesson folder
The sixth lesson
And this is the AI slash
So
Then we'll open this up
After opening it
We'll select the interpreter we configured earlier
Meaning we are developing in a virtual environment
I set up the virtual environment using Anaconda
When we installed Anaconda
We already created a virtual environment
That is, AI-service
If you're unsure how to create it,
check out the previous lesson on setting up the environment.
It's covered there.
So here, we can just select this one.
This one has only one environment.
If you have multiple environments, you can choose from them.
The benefit of a virtual environment is isolation.
Each virtual environment is isolated from the others.
And here, it will help us create a script environment.
A script is like a demo.
Let's click to create.
This field cannot be empty.
I'll delete this.
It's already been created.
If you haven't created it yet,
it's no problem.
you won't encounter this error.
Let's create it.
So, once this is created,
let's take a look at this area,
which is our project directory,
we currently have only one script,
which is a Python script,
it's a scripting language,
now let's check out this section,
where we select the virtual environment,
we've already selected it.
So, we don't need to make any changes here.
Then, we can directly click to run it.
Let's see what it prints out directly.
Next, we'll explain the meaning of this part.
First, if you have studied C language,
if you have a background in C language,
it's a bit different from what we have here.
The 'f' here is used to define our function.
That is, it's used as a decorator.
This is one of our functions.
Overall, this is the function.
If you have absolutely no programming background,
what does this function mean?
You can think of this function as a tool.
We encapsulate some complex logic
into this function.
And when we need to use it later,
we can simply call this function.
This way, it's like we're modularizing things.
Turns out, one of the core ideas in programming is modularity.
Modular programming involves encapsulating functionalities.
We wrap these functionalities in functions.
Encapsulating them into a cohesive unit.
This makes it easier for others to use later on.
Otherwise, if you don't encapsulate them,
Each function would be written on the fly, which
Would be quite troublesome.
Your code looks a bit messy too.
That's why functions come into play.
If we've learned C, we know that
We need to add a return type at the beginning.
If there's no return value,
it's with.
If there is one,
we need to specify the return types for in as well.
However, Python has a more relaxed syntax.
It doesn't need to be added.
It will automatically infer it.
So, what do you want to return here?
You can return anything casually.
For this return, let's just return a string, shall we?
Or you can return an integer; both are fine.
It will automatically infer it.
This kind of writing is perfectly fine.
We won't get any errors here.
And if you're here,
if you want to get the return value,
you can also get this one,
this is how it's written in Python,
unlike C and Java,
C requires strict syntax for writing,
the return type must be specified,
and the same goes for this part,
all parameters must be passed when fully specified.
This also needs to be written in this type, right?
But Python doesn't require that.
It's a derivation process of the posts.
For those without programming experience,
Remember this keyword, def.
Of course, if you're doing C, you need to remember it as well.
Def is a keyword,
a keyword used for this purpose.
It's a function.
Keep this in mind
Remember this keyword
Then this part can be named whatever you like
This is the function name
It's just a label
You get the idea
You can name it anything
But it can't start with a number
Everything else is fine
So then
This place here is for the parameters we pass in
In C, you have to write this parameter, um
It’s an int type, right?
If you pass an int type
You have to write all of them as int types
But here, it’s not necessary
We don’t need to here; it’s a loosely typed programming language
Then we pass in a label, which is also a tag.
This name is also a tag.
You can name it whatever you like; it’s a parameter.
What does the parameter do?
It’s passed in.
This one here is also a function.
It’s from the system library.
It’s a function found in the standard library.
This is the output.
Print a message to this console.
This is pretty simple.
This is what we do when writing programs.
Like when we develop software.
It’s usually hello world, right?
Just type hello world here.
Here it says H time, doesn’t it?
Let’s take a look.
This is just a print statement.
Print out this passed parameter
Then, for the definition of F
It means that this requires the use of curly braces in this way
Then, pass all the parameters in
It will print out
This is also a function call
The function itself is quite complex
But why is it so simple to use
This is the benefit of encapsulation
This encapsulates a complex feature into a function.
The function serves one purpose.
Then, is return also a keyword?
Those who have written C definitely know this.
Most programming languages are familiar with this.
They all have the return statement.
When it comes to returning a value.
In our previous experience with C.
You must return a value.
If it returns an int
you need to add an int here, right?
but C doesn't have a define define
and for this
we don't need to define anything for the return
we can directly receive it here
just receive it here
and when receiving, we don't need to use anything like
an int to name it either
It's all automatically derived.
Then we can print this out.
This has the unified zero code added.
After you hit Enter,
it will prompt you to press the Tab key.
Press the Tab key.
It automatically fills it in for you.
This is like AI-assisted coding.
Now let's run it again.
Let's take a look.
You see, it printed 11 as well.
That's the value it returns.
You can do whatever you want here.
Let's create a string.
This is a string.
Enclosed in double quotes.
A string type.
The int type, of course, is for numbers, not strings.
Like NAAA or something.
Numbers, right?
Numbers are of the int type.
They don't need to be enclosed in double quotes.
It's an int type, an integer.
Anything enclosed in double or single quotes is a string.
It's all pretty flexible.
It's quite casual, really.
Python programming is quite flexible
And then there's C language
It uses curly braces to denote the body of a function
You need to wrap the curly braces around the code
But in Python, indentation is used to indicate this
This is what the indentation looks like
As you can see, it's usually a tab key
The indentation shows that this much is part of a function
If you continue on the next line, it's still part of it
Of course, you can't return it from here.
It's still a function problem.
If you start a new line here,
it won't be part of this function anymore.
It follows the indentation for the overall structure.
Let's take a look at what this means here.
If we talk about the double underscore name here,
it's a variable within this.
You can think of it this way.
A label
You can temporarily understand it as
It's a special variable, that's all
If you run it directly here
It will assign this name to this underscore
May
Just like that
And when you run it here
It will execute this segment of code
It will execute the code inside.
The code you've written.
If this is for others to use.
The entire file is for others to use.
Then it won't execute here.
This makes unit testing more convenient.
We test the code we've written, right?
We test it here.
To see if the code is correct.
This is more convenient for testing.
That's the idea.
Similarly, here.
You can see it's calling a function.
It's done this way.
You've written a function here.
Now I'm calling it here, right?
If you want to use it.
First, you need to pass parameters.
If there are parameters, you need to pass them in.
Second, there's a return value.
It doesn't matter whether you receive it or not.
If you need this return value.
You should receive it.
If you don't need it.
You don't have to receive it.
This is also fine.
This is how you write a function.
The function is like this.
And that's it for this lesson.